lots of contradicting opinions about ACG
along with trt regardless of fertility
and the desire to have kids generally
speaking is it a good idea or not and
why who wants to sort yeah I'll I'll
jump in on that one if you like um so so
yeah it's it's it's a big debate isn't
it so you'll anecdotally when uh you
work clinically you'll see patients that
get on great with HCG and then patients
that do not tolerate it well at all um
and now you know in terms of uh its
efficacy I know they said you know they
didn't really uh mind about sort of
fertility or having kids or anything
like that um there are other benefits if
you do if you are able to tolerate it
well so there's the preservation of
testicular volume um so it it can have a
preventative effect on particular
atrophy which obviously is something
that is uh seen on testosterone
monotherapy um but uh it also can
confer uh benefits in terms of olical
well-being like so you'll see people say
that they feel uh just that little bit
better or they sometimes refer to it as
that missing piece of the jigsa um that
where they just feel sort of better on
trt when they add in HCG um but then uh
you know on the on the flip side you
will get multiple patients that that
have horrendous anxiety and you'll
eliminate any other factors that you can
and then finally you'll remove the HCG
and that seems to sort things for them
so it's uh you know in terms of the
evidence it's it can be beneficial uh
for lots of reasons but not all patients
tolerate it well clinically in our
experience I think what about you
Angela yeah no absolutely I think it's
really interesting you you made the
point about for some people it's the
missing piece you very rarely find a
patient who's on the fence about HCG
it's either been utterly awful um or
really good um and there's not really
not really many people is sort of in the
middle about it but for me um some
people that I would really be more
cautious about it was with people would
be people who struggled with significant
anxiety in the past because actually um
anxiety does seem to be a feature if
you're going to experience side effects
um post HCG one that seems to sort of
stand out um but yeah like Felix it says
it's some you know sometimes it's um it
can actually end up being the missing
piece for some individuals
so yeah but trying to say is is it a
good idea I think is is is very patient
specific like you'll you'll either get
on with it or you
won't yeah absolutely
[Music]